Oh hi! I'm **Annelise Smith**.

I'm a **UX designer and published pyschology researcher** with a knack for building genuine connections and asking the right questions to get to the root of users' needs and pain points. My superpower is translating data into effective solutions that solve both user and business needs.

annelisesmithux@gmail.com bestuxdesignerever.com

Experience

UX Designer at Dive Around the Clock Seattle, WA | Oct 2016 - May 2017

- -Improved alignment of website with user needs by implementing primary user research plan, including interviews, usability testing, and behavioral observation.
- -Developed site maps and wireframes that enable intuitive navigation.
- -Increased click-through to donation and volunteer registration pages.

UX Instructional Associate at General Assembly

Seattle, WA | Jan 2017 - May 2017

- -Taught UX research and design in an immersive UX design course.
- -Led user research, usability testing, and interviewing workshops.
- -Provided critiques and feedback on user research strategy for design projects.
- -Updated and designed curriculum to align with current industry standards.

Field Marketing Specialist at Hershey Company

Seattle, WA | Oct 2015 - Sept 2016

-Devised, organized, and oversaw execution of guerrilla marketing campaigns to drive product awareness and foster brand loyalty for Krave Jerky.

Child Protective Services Investigator at Dept. of Social & Health Services

Tacoma, WA | Oct 2014 - Oct 2015

- -Conducted in-home interviews to identify core family problems and make legal. decisions about child safety in high-stress situations.
- -Analyzed information to design safety plans using existing community resources
- -Created accurate documentation while meeting strict legal dealines.

Program Evaluation Consultant at Freelance

Tacoma, WA | Jun 2012 - Oct 2015

-Collaborated with non-profits to create logic models, build and implement data collection plans, and analyze program data to inform decision-making.

Research Associate at Washington State University

Pullman, WA | Aug 2012- Aug 2013

- -Created and supervised implementation of data collection/analysis plans.
- -Developed evaluation plans for student health promotion programs.
- -Designed, implemented, and evaluated social media health campaigns.
- -Authored research briefs/literature reviews to support decision-making.

Research Coordinator at Washington State University

Pullman, WA | Aug 2011- Aug 2012

- -Managed the daily functioning of a 2-year NIH-funded research program.
- -Supervised 12 research assistants and 30 program volunteers.
- -Oversaw collection, coding, and analysis of qualitative/quantitative study data.
- -Authored scholarly publications and presented findings to stakeholder groups.

Top skills

User Research Usability Testing Ethnography Survey Design Personas Affinity Mapping Journey Mapping Content Analysis Wireframing Paper Prototyping Hi-fi Prototyping Mobile Design

Tools I use

Axure POP Sketch SPSS InVision Stata

OmniGraffle MS Office Suite

HTML/CSS Keynote

Balsamiq Adobe Illustrator

Published in...

Journal of Primary Prevention Journal of Extension Human-Animal Interaction Bulletin

Awards I've won

First Place- CalPal (Alexa Skill) General Assembly Hackathon (2016)

First Place -AFW Founders Award for Outstanding Graduate Student Washington State University (2013)

Education

UX Design Immersive (2016) General Assembly

MA Human Development (2013) Developmental Psychology Focus Washington State University

BA Social Sciences (2011)

Washington State University Minor in Comparative Ethnic Studies Minor in German